1.  [Customer services](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/)
2.  Privacy policy

Privacy policy
==============

**About this Privacy policy**
-----------------------------

We know how important it is for you to understand how we use your data. This Privacy Policy explains how we use any personal data you provide us with when you use our services in our stores, online via our Website and the IKEA App, through your IKEA Family membership, and any contact you have with our Customer Support Centre. This Privacy Policy covers both private customers and business customers.

We will always be transparent with you about what we do with your personal data. We only collect, store and process your personal data in accordance with the relevant laws and regulations.

This Privacy Policy also explains your rights in relation to the personal data that we collect about you. We respect your right to privacy and are committed to maintaining it. By accessing and browsing our website you are confirming that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy, so please make sure you have read it carefully.

We are IKEA Ireland Limited (“IKEA” or “we”, “us”), and our registered address is 6th Floor, 2 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2. IKEA is the “data controller” of any personal data we may collect, process and hold about you, unless we inform you otherwise.

*   What?
    
    **1\. What personal data do we collect?**
    -----------------------------------------
    
    Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).
    
    The personal data we collect from you and process may include:
    
    *   Your name and title
    *   Your email address
    *   Your mobile telephone number
    *   Your date of birth
    *   Your address
    *   Your IKEA Family card number
    *   Your purchasing activity
    *   Your credit or debit card, or other payment information
    *   Your account password and login details
    *   Your preferred store
    *   Your comments, product reviews and responses on surveys you complete
    *   Your interactions with any marketing emails sent from us to you
    *   Any shopping preferences or details to help us suggest items for you
    *   Your images on CCTV and security body worn cameras
    *   Your car number plate if recorded to manage parking at our stores, or to detect vehicles of interest for the purposes of prevention and detection of crime
    *   Information about your device type
    *   Website / browsing history, including location data
    *   Cookie information (please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/cookie-policy/) for details)
    
    It may also include any information you give us:
    
    *   When you contact or are contacted by; our customer services, remote sales, planning or remote planning teams.
    *   When you contact or are contacted by our legal teams.
    *   When you engage with our social media platforms (for example by tagging us in a post on Instagram or commenting during one of our live-streams)
    *   When you sign up for IKEA Family membership and engage with IKEA Family membership benefits, such as recommendations based on your prior purchases at IKEA and reward points.
    *   When you make an appointment with us (for example, appointment booking information and any information given during the appointment)
    
    If you are using a mobile device and shopping with us online or browsing our website, and logging onto WIFI in store using your laptop or mobile we may collect:
    
    *   your IP address or other device identifier,
    *   your browser type and version,
    *   your time zone setting,
    *   operating system and platform
    
    Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.
    
    **Third Parties**
    
    We work with a number of third parties to provide goods and services, such as our last mile delivery providers, in-store minicab concessions, in-store rental car and van providers, IKEA Kitchen Services and TaskRabbit, our assembly serviceInternalproviders. These providers may collect personal data directly from you to organise and book their services, or for their own marketing and tracking purposes. If they do collect your personal data, they will be acting as Data Controllers in their own right, separately from IKEA. If they use your personal data, their own privacy policies will apply and they should provide you with access to their privacy policy at the time that they collect your personal data.
    
    Where you are using a mobile device whilst in store with its WiFi capability switched on and access our free in-store WiFi, we may additionally collect your location and device data whilst you are within the IKEA store or immediately within its perimeters. We use this information on an anonymous basis and will never use it to identify any particular user. We won't be able to link this data to any other data that we hold about you and the purpose of collecting this data is to perform analysis and to help us identify people flows around our stores to maximise the efficiency of our store design. If you do not want us to track your device or use your information in this way, please disconnect from our free in-store WiFi and turn off the WiFi capability on your phone or other electronic device within your settings.
    
    We may, where we have a lawful basis for doing so, also collect personal data about you from third parties, or companies who have obtained your permission to share this information with us, or who need to share information with us in relation to goods or services you have purchased. When we work with such third parties, you would have been informed about this data sharing at the time of collection. We use this and our own data to better understand our customers and their needs.
    
    We do not knowingly solicit personal data from children or send them requests for personal data. We acknowledge that visitors of all ages may use our website, however, we do not intentionally collect personal data from those under the age of 18.
    
*   When?
    
    **2\. When do we collect your personal data?**
    ----------------------------------------------
    
    *   When you purchase products and services from us in store, online, using the IKEA App or over the phone
    *   When processing requests for tax invoices related to purchases made in store or online
    *   When you access our website or use any of our mobile apps, our website also uses cookies; to find out more about the use of cookies and how you can manage them, please read our [Cookie policy](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/cookie-policy/)
    *   When you have your WiFi settings switched on and are logged into our in-store WiFi•
    *   When you join our IKEA Family loyalty club
    *   When you contact us or we contact you to take part in surveys, competitions or promotions• When you register for in store events or activities
    *   When you provide feedback using our digital tools both in store and online
    *   When you contact or are contacted by our Customer Services, sales and planning teams whilst in store, via online, over the phone or via web chat
    *   When you engage with us on social media (by mentioning/tagging us or by contacting us directly)
    *   When your image may be captured via our CCTV system or body camera worn by our security team. Your car number plate may also be captured by our ANPR system
    
*   How?
    
    **3\. How do we use your personal data and what are our legal justifications for doing so?**
    --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
    
    There are a number of different reasons why we might use your personal data, depending on what type of data you have provided. You do not have to provide any of this personal data to us but if you don’t, we might not be able to make our products and services available to you, your overall shopping experience may be less personalised and it is less likely that you will receive our best overall customer experience.
    
    This list shows how we use your personal data and why:
    
    ### **Personal data: Your name and contact details**
    
    #### **How we use this personal data:**
    
    1.  To fulfil your order, take payment from you i.e. taking payment, update you regarding the status of your order and shipping the order to you (including the printing of labels).  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)** We rely on our contractual arrangements with you as the lawful basis on which we collect and process your personal data when you make an order for products and services.
    2.  To provide a tax invoice to you related to your in store or online purchase  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        We rely on our contractual arrangements with you as the lawful basis on which we collect and process your personal data when you make an order for products and services.
    3.  To manage any issues during order fulfilment, including Click and Collect, to manage your returns, exchanges and refunds, and to manage and process planning, measuring and remote sales appointments.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)** We've got to do this to perform our contract with you. We may also keep a record of this to comply with our legal obligations.
    4.  To sign you up to receive our email Newsletters by submitting your details via our online form.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        You consent to receive our email Newsletters if you chose to sign up by completing and submitting our online form. You can opt out of these at any time through your account settings.
    5.  To register you for an IKEA Family membership account..  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        We've got to do this to perform our contract with you.
    6.  To update you regarding your IKEA Family account.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        We've got to do this to perform our contract with you.
    7.  To send you offers, promotions and events for IKEA Family members.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)** IKEA relies upon your consent to send you promotions relevant to the IKEA Family scheme and your chosen interests within your profile. You can opt out of these at any time through your account settings.
    8.  To send you service communications, conveying a specific message unrelated to marketing purposes.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has a legitimate interest to communicate with you on occasion, to support your experience with us.
    9.  To create e-receipts, for online purchases, and to connect your in-store receipts to your Family membership account.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has a legitimate interest to ensure e-Receipts are provided to a valid email address.
    10.  To verify your identity when you access your IKEA profile, IKEA Family Membership Account, or to contact you to perform security checks when you speak to Customer Services.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has legitimate interest in ensuring that you are who you say you are to ensure goods and services are provided to the correct person.
    11.  In the detection and prevention of fraud or other crimes.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has legitimate interest in protecting itself from Fraud.
    12.  To receive your feedback whilst in store and online and monitor how happy you were with your visit.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has legitimate interest in improving our customer experience.
    13.  To monitor and improve the services and the Website, including monitoring browsing activity and session replays.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has legitimate interest in monitoring the websites to improve customer experience.
    14.  To be able to return any lost and found items to you or record any incidents or accidents in store.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         You have legitimate interest in providing this information to IKEA to ensure we can manage any of the occurrences that may occur in store.
    15.  To send you an email that you have abandoned your basket or, for existing customers (subject to your preferences), where we send you updates on items you have been browsing.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has legitimate interest to sell its products, including checking to see if customers want to continue processing their order.
    16.  To invite you to take part in surveys such as pulse CX, abandon basket and the IKEA App, online surveys on the website NPS – rate and reviews industry benchmark, search survey – how happy were you with search result.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has a legitimate interest in selling its products and improving our customer experience. We don't need your consent to send you these communications, but they will not include any promotional content unless you have opted-in to receive marketing from us. We use responses from surveys to monitor and improve the quality of our products and services and your overall customer experience.
    17.  To send you marketing promotions, offers, competitions and events by email, post, phone and SMS for IKEA goods and services, (subject to your preferences). Please see the section below on Marketing for more information.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         We will do this based on the consent you give us when you register with us online or join the IKEA Family membership. You are free to opt-out of receiving these communications at any time.
    18.  To secure a place for you at events you have requested to attend.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has a legitimate interest in managing capacity for the events it provides.
    19.  To administer any prize draws or competitions that you choose to enter. We sometimes use third parties to help us do this - we will make this clear in the terms and conditions of the prize draw or competition.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         We will do this based on the consent you give us when you enter. If a third party will use these details to contact you directly as part of the prize draw or competition, we will ask for your consent to that third party contacting you.
    20.  To send you communications via selected channels push notifications that you sign up to via your personal device to keep you up to date with our latest offers, products and promotions.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         We will do this based on the consent you give us when you sign up to receive these notifications. You can stop receiving these at any time. Please see our Marketing section for more details.
    21.  To process and manage your booking/appointment.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         We've got to do this to perform our contract with you and to enable us to set up the appointment and arrange this with you.
    22.  To combine aggregated information about our customers (that doesn't identify those customers) to help us track performance and improve the services we offer. Some of this data will be shared with selected third parties such as Google Analytics etc.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has legitimate interest in analysing this information to improve customer experience.
    23.  To send you service emails or communications required by law to update you about any changes to our goods and services, any information required by law relating to your order or product recalls.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         We need to do this to comply with our legal obligations. We don't need your consent to send you these communications, but they will not include any promotional content.
    24.  To develop and test any changes or improvements to our websites, goods or services.  
         **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
         IKEA has legitimate interest in developing and testing our goods and services to improve customer experience.
    
    ### **Personal data: Your payment details**
    
    #### **How we use this personal data:**
    
    1.  To fulfil your order, i.e. taking payment, updating you regarding the status of your order and shipping the order to you. As well as managing any issues during order fulfilment.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        We've got to do this to perform our contract with you and our contracts with partners and suppliers who work with us to provide a service to you.
    2.  To analyse customer spend within our stores and online.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has legitimate interest in analysing this information to improve customer experience.
    
    ### **Personal data: Your login and Password**
    
    #### **How we use this personal data:**
    
    1.  To verify your identity when you access your account.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has legitimate interest in ensuring that you are who you say you are to ensure goods and services are provided to the correct person.
    
    ### **Personal data: Your device information, preferences and cookies provided when you browse our website** 
    
    #### **How we use this personal data:**
    
    1.  To tailor your experience online and send you personalised emails (in combination with other information you have provided us or our third parties) so that we can offer you goods and services and promotions, offers and events we think you will be interested in.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        We will do this where you have consented to the use of cookies on our database. Please see our section on Cookies and our Cookie Policy for more details. You can manage your cookie settings at any time.
    2.  To show you advertising on such Social Media platforms as Facebook and Twitter or third party advertising that may appear on other websites you use.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        We will do this where you have consented to the use of cookies on our database. Please see our section on Cookies and our Cookie Policy for more details. You can manage your cookie settings at any time.
    3.  To combine the information that we collect directly from you with any information that we obtain from third parties to whom you have given your consent to pass that data onto us, such as the Social Media platforms and publicly available information we describe above.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has legitimate interest in understanding our customers and what will interest them for the best customer experience. This also helps us identify trends in different countries which helps us to better understand our customers in those countries.
    4.  To combine with personal data that we collect directly from you (including survey responses) with any information that we obtain from third parties in order to classify our customers into segments, using shopping habits information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experiences with our products and contact preferences.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has legitimate interest in understanding our customers and what will interest them for the best customer experience. These segments help us to understand our customers better. To the extent we receive data from third parties, this will be based on the permission you have given that third party to share your data with us.
    
    ### **Personal data: Device information and details when using our Wi-Fi**
    
    #### **How we use this personal data:**
    
    We do this to allow you to use our in-store Wi-Fi service. We use ‘Yo Wireless’ to provide the Wi-Fi.  
    **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
    We've got to do this to perform our contract with you. We will also ask you if you want to consent to email marketing through this registration.
    
    ### **Personal data: Information about yourself that you choose to submit or post as part of your IKEA Family membership or that relates to your activities in the IKEA Family** 
    
    #### **How we use this personal data:**
    
    1.  We do this to promote the IKEA Family and IKEA products in marketing campaigns using content that has been posted by our IKEA Family members. Please see the IKEA Family Terms of Use for further information.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has a legitimate interest in promoting the IKEA Family and IKEA products to our customers. You are free to edit or remove your content from the IKEA Family at any time.
    2.  To administer, store and deduct as appropriate; “IKEA Reward Keys” for applicable activities linked to your IKEA Family Membership. Please see the IKEA Family Terms of Use for further information.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has a legitimate interest to award it’s members via this loyalty scheme for taking part in applicable activities.
    
    ### **Personal data: Financial information, social media information**
    
    #### **How we use this personal data:**
    
    When combined with personal identification and contact details to investigate cases of fraud.  
    **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
    IKEA has legitimate interest in protecting ourselves from various types of fraud.
    
    ### **Personal data: Your image on CCTV**
    
    #### **How we use this personal data:**
    
    1.  To ensure the safety and security of colleagues and customers and the prevention or detection of unlawful acts.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA has legitimate interest in protecting itself from crime, and to provide a safe working environment for our staff.
    2.  To administer parking regulations in those car parks which are linked to our Stores.  
        **Why we do it (lawful basis)**   
        IKEA works with the third party operators of the car parks and has legitimate interest to ensure that these parking regulations are adhered to.
    
    ### **To make our products and services available to you**
    
    We use your personal data to provide you with the information, products and services that you request or purchase from us (i.e. to complete certain tasks, processes or orders on our website or within our apps, take payment online (where applicable) and deliver your products or services), and to communicate with you regarding those products and services that you purchase from us and respond to your questions and comments;
    
    We may also use your personal data to measure how satisfied our customers are and provide customer service (including troubleshooting in connection with purchases or your requests for services or when you ask us questions on social media);
    
    Alternatively, in some cases, we rely on our legitimate interests as a business (for example, to measure customer satisfaction and troubleshoot customer issues). Where we rely on our legitimate interests, we will always make sure that we balance these interests against your rights.
    
    ### **For administrative and internal business purposes**
    
    We may use your personal data for our internal business purposes, such as enhancing our site, improving our services and products and identifying usage trends. We may also use your data to monitor the use of our website and ensure that our website is presented in the most effective and relevant manner for you and your device and setting default options for you (such as language and store location);
    
    It is in our legitimate interests as a business to use your personal data in this way. For example, we want to ensure our website is customer friendly and works properly and that our products and services are efficient and of high quality. We also want to make it easy for you to interact with us. Where we rely on our legitimate interests, we will always make sure that we balance these interests against your rights.
    
    ### **For security and legal reasons**
    
    We use your personal data to:
    
    *   ensure the personal and financial information you provide us is accurate;• conduct fraud checks or prevent other illegal activity;
    *   protect our rights or property (or those of others); and
    *   fulfil our legal and compliance-related obligations.
    
    In some cases, we will use your personal data because it's necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation (such as if we receive a legitimate request from a law enforcement agency). In other cases (such as the detection of fraud) we will rely on our legitimate interests as a business to use your personal data in this way. Where we rely on our legitimate interests, we will always make sure that we balance these interests against your rights.
    
    For the purposes of safety, detection and prevention of crime, IKEA will use its legitimate interests to share certain information with third parties with which it has data processing agreements. This may include CCTV and other potentially identifiable information collected during IKEA's monitoring, detection, crime and safety activities.
    
    ### **In relation to your IKEA Family membership**
    
    We use your personal data to personalise your experience with IKEA to:
    
    *   provide you with marketing material via SMS, post and email if you have given us your consent to this;
    *   process your registration details, account activity and purchase history to analyse how you shop and what you shop for. This may include information on products you have viewed, historical transactions and products you have added to your online basket. This allows us to provide a browsing experience which is relevant to you;
    *   manage your reward keys balance based on purchases and interactions you have with us;
    *   in some instances we will send specific offers to our members based on their in-store spend or on a special occasion such as when we know it's your birthday;
    *   measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns and our advertising;
    *   carry out limited automated decision making based on the information you have given us when we segment our
    
    We rely on your consent to send direct SMS, postal and email marketing messages to you as an IKEA Family member based on the consent we acquired from you when you signed up, as amended by you from time to time.
    
    In other cases (for example, measuring the effectiveness of our marketing), we will rely on our legitimate interests as a business to communicate with our IKEA Family members in an engaging and efficient way. Where we rely on our legitimate interests, we will always make sure that we balance these interests against your rights.
    
    ### **To personalise your shopping experience and improve our operations**
    
    We use your personal data to:
    
    *   allow you to create a profile on our website which enables you to purchase IKEA products and services online without having to fill in your personal data every time you shop online with us;
    *   provide you with marketing material via SMS and email;
    *   analyse how you shop and what you shop for. This may include information on products you have viewed, historical transactions and products you have added to your online basket. This allows us to provide a browsing experience which is relevant to you.
    
    It is in our legitimate interests as a business to use your data in this way and we do this in order to enhance your shopping experience with us. This allows us to help you find the products and services which you may be looking for and avoids you having to browse through products or services which are not relevant to you.When we send you marketing material via SMS, and email, we will rely on our legitimate interests as a business, always ensuring that your rights are protected.For information on how we use cookies, please see our [Cookie policy](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/cookie-policy/).
    
*   Who?
    
    **4\. Who do we share your personal data with?**
    ------------------------------------------------
    
    We will never sell any of your personal data to a third party. However, in order for us to provide our services to you, we share your personal data with our trusted third party service providers or our group companies, as detailed below. Whenever we share your personal data, we put safeguards in place which require these organisations to keep your data safe and to ensure that they do not use your personal data for their own marketing purposes.
    
    ### **Third party service providers**
    
    **To fulfil orders for products and services**
    
    We work with a number of trusted service providers who carry out services on our behalf. When you purchase products and services from us, the services provided by these organisations includes delivery, product assembly and installation, waste removal and processing payments. We also work with a service provider to administer our gift card and account services Additionally, we also work with a service provider to support our customer support centre, for store and product enquires, or issues with goods and services purchased from us. It is in our legitimate interests as a business to work with these service providers since we may not have the capabilities to provide these services ourselves. In each case, we will ensure that the service provider is only allowed to use your personal data in order to provide the services to us and for no other purpose.
    
    **To prevent crime and comply with laws**
    
    We share your financial information including your credit, debit card or other payment information with third parties to ensure that your payment is safe and that your details are not being used fraudulently. This data sharing enables us to conduct fraud analysis which ensures that genuine and accurate payment details are provided to us for any purchase. We may share your personal data with credit agencies if you are requesting credit.
    
    There may be other scenarios where we are subject to a legal obligation to share or disclose your personal data, such as with law enforcement agencies or public authorities in order to prevent or detect crime or fulfil a legal requirement.
    
    For the purposes of preventing crime, IKEA will use its legitimate interests to share certain information with third parties with which it has data processing agreements. This may include CCTV and other potentially identifiable information collected during IKEA's monitoring, detection, crime and safety activities.
    
    **Other professional services**
    
    We may need to disclose your personal data to our insurers where we believe that it is required under our contractual relationship with our insurance provider to do so.
    
    We work with carefully selected third parties, such as our customer database hosting provider, marketing agencies and advertising partners who assist us in providing you with a positive customer experience. We work with these third parties to place relevant content and advertisements for you on our website, other websites and online media channels and apps. In order to do this, we use pixels and cookies. You can see our [**Cookie policy**](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/cookie-policy/).
    
    ### **Group companies**
    
    We may share the personal data we collect with other organisations in the IKEA Group where those other companies share various operations and business processes with us (such as IKEA Ireland Limited, IKEA IT AB, IKEA of Sweden AB). We will do this in order to fulfil our contractual obligations to you, or because it is in our legitimate interests to do so.
    
    ### **Transfer of your personal data outside the EEA**
    
    We may need to transfer your personal data within the European Economic Area (EEA) or to another third country, for example the UK, USA or India, in the following circumstances:
    
    *   Where you have requested a service which is fulfilled by one of our group companies which sit in another country of the EEA or another third country; or
    *   Where we work with a supplier which processes some of its personal data within another country of the EEA or another third country.
    
    For any personal data transfers to the UK or within the EEA, we will continue to follow all regulatory and legal requirements set out in the EU-UK Trade and Cooperation Agreement, and any subsequent arrangements that are agreed.Other third countries may not have the same data protection laws as the UK and the EEA and so your personal data may not be subject to the same protections. However, in such cases, we will make sure that any transfer of your personal data to countries outside the UK and EEA is subject to appropriate safeguards as if it were being processed inside the UK or EEA and under the guiding principles set out in this privacy policy.
    
    If you would like further information please **[contact us](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/contact-us/)**.
    
*   Your rights
    
    **5\. Your rights**
    -------------------
    
    You have a number of rights relating to your personal data and what happens to it. You are entitled to:
    
    *   have your data processed in a fair, lawful and transparent way;
    *   be informed about how your personal data is being used, an example being this privacy policy;
    *   access personal data we hold about you;
    *   require us to correct any mistakes in your personal data;
    *   require us to delete personal data concerning you in certain situations where there is no good reason for us to continue to process it;
    *   request that we transfer your personal data to you or another service provider in a simple, structured format;
    *   object at any time to processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes;
    *   object to automated decision-making which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you;
    *   object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal data;
    *   withdraw consent provided by you; and
    *   otherwise restrict or temporarily stop our processing of your personal data in certain circumstances.
    
    You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights).
    
    We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
    
    We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one calendar month. Occasionally it could take us longer than this if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
    
    You can read more about your rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, in the Guidance from the Irish Data Protection Commissioner (DPC) https://www.dataprotection.ie/. You also have the right to complain about our use of personal data to the DPC. You can do these by contacting the DPC via their website https://www.dataprotection.ie/en/contact/how-contact-us or by emailing info@dataprotection.ie. If you would like to speak to us in relation to any of your rights, please **[contact us](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/contact-us/)**.
    
*   Changing your preferences
    
    **6\. Changing your preferences**
    ---------------------------------
    
    If you no longer wish to be contacted by us about our products or services, or for other marketing purposes, you can amend your preferences or unsubscribe by contacting us. Alternatively, if you have a profile on the IKEA website or have downloaded the IKEA App, you can unsubscribe by logging into your account, or simply follow the unsubscribe link provided in emails you receive from us.
    
    We want to ensure that all the information we have about our customers is factually correct and up to date. If you find that the personal data we have about you is inaccurate or needs updating (for instance, you may have changed your name or address) then please contact us so that we can correct it. If you have created a profile on the IKEA website or IKEA App, you can change the details stored about you by logging into your account.
    
*   Security and retention
    
    **7\. Security and retention of your personal data**
    ----------------------------------------------------
    
    **Security of your personal data**
    
    We take the security of your personal data very seriously. We have implemented various strategies, controls, policies and measures to keep your data secure and keep these measures under close review. We protect your data by using encryption techniques and we use other safeguards such as firewalls and password protection. This means that your data is protected and only accessible by co-workers who need it to carry out their job responsibilities. We also ensure that there are strict physical controls in our buildings which restricts access to your personal data to keep it safe.
    
    **Retention of your personal data**
    
    In broad terms, we will only retain your personal data for as long as is necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy policy. This means that the retention periods will vary according to the type of the data and the reason that we have the data in the first place.
    
    To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
    
    Personal information will be deleted/destroyed or anonymized at the end of the retention period.
    
*   Special Category Data
    
    **8\. Special Category Data**
    -----------------------------
    
    Certain categories of personal data have additional protection under the UK GDPR. The categories include information about your health, racial or ethnic origin.
    
    IKEA processes special category data where this is provided by you during the course of correspondence with us to inform us of any delivery/assistance requirements or as part of a complaint or grievance procedure or in relation to an accident or incident which has occurred on our premises. IKEA will process this information to provide you with the assistance you have requested or to deal with your complaint. Where you have asked us to provide assistance or special delivery instructions, we will do this on the basis of your consent to us using it in this way. Where we are processing this information in order to deal with a complaint, this processing will be necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims made by or against us.
    
*   Marketing
    
    **9\. Marketing**
    -----------------
    
    If you have given us your contact details, we may use these (in accordance with any preferences you have expressed) to send you marketing messages by email, SMS and post, to keep you aware of what we're up to and to help you see and find our products. This includes sending tips and inspiration for your home, details of special offers, services and promotions from IKEA.
    
    As part of running our business, IKEA has a **legitimate interest** to promote our products using marketing messages to existing customers of IKEA and those in a negotiation with us for a sale or service, unless you have asked us not to.
    
    When we collect your personal data, we give you the opportunity to opt-in to receive those marketing messages by simply ticking the boxes. Should you change your mind, we have lots of ways you can stop receiving marketing messages, which we've set out below.If you are currently opted-out of our marketing, you can always choose to opt-in to receive our emails by amending your preferences.
    
    ### **How to stop marketing messages from IKEA**
    
    You can stop receiving marketing messages from us at any time.
    
    For email marketing, the best way to do this is to click on the 'unsubscribe' link in any email you receive. You can also go onto your online profile, and on the IKEA App.
    
    You can opt out of other marketing as follows:
    
    *   For direct mail – in all our direct mail communications, we offer the opportunity to opt out by mail, you can also opt out on your online profile
    *   In all our SMS communications, you can also opt out on your online profile
    *   For targeted or personalised adverts – by opting out of cookies – see cookie policy for more details
    
    It might take some time for all our systems to be updated, so you might get messages from us while we fully process your request, but we will ensure that we mark you as having opted out on our database as soon as we receive your request.
    
    You can also amend your preferences at any time by logging into your account and navigating to the settings page.
    
    Please be aware that stopping marketing messages will not stop our service communications (such as order and delivery updates).
    
*   Automated decision-making and Profiling
    
    **10\. Automated decision-making and Profiling**
    ------------------------------------------------
    
    We bring together different information you have given us or we have collected from your interactions with IKEA in store, through remote services, via the app or on the web and perform analytics to segment customers into groups to personalise and improve the shopping experience. We may use this information to determine which offers you may be interested in where you have opted into being contacted for marketing purposes or for automated decision making to improve your shopping experience like recommending products and services, or improving your experience with remote services.
    
*   AI Assistant for voice
    
    11\. AI Assistant for voice
    ---------------------------
    
    During your experience as an IKEA customer, you may encounter the use of AI, for example when you call our customer service. This includes the use of an AI assistant to answer common questions quickly. If the AI assistant cannot help, or if you ask to speak to a co-worker, your call will be transferred to the co-worker.The use of the AI assistant is intended to make it easier and faster for you to get the help you need. This is based on our legitimate interest in improving customer service and reducing waiting times. The personal data used may include contact details, order information and the questions you ask during the call.
    
*   Cookies
    
    **12\. Cookies**
    ----------------
    
    Cookies are small encrypted text files that are stored on your device by a website. Our Websites use cookies to enable you to shop, enhance your shopping experience and to analyse our traffic.
    
    For further information visit [https://www.dataprotection.ie/en/dpc-guidance/guidance-on-cookies-and-similar-technologies](https://www.dataprotection.ie/en/dpc-guidance/guidance-on-cookies-and-similar-technologies)
    
    You can set your browser not to accept cookies and the above website tells you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, in a few cases some of our Website features may not function as a result.Our Cookie Policy is set out here.
    
    Our Cookie Policy is set out [here.](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/cookie-policy/)
    
*   Changes
    
    **13\. Changes to this Privacy policy**
    ---------------------------------------
    
    We may update this Privacy policy from time to time. If we make significant changes, we will let you know but please regularly check this policy to ensure you are aware of the most updated version.
    
*   Contact
    
    **14\. Contact**
    ----------------
    
    If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or your rights under it, please contact
    
    Philip Cooke – IKEA UK&IE Data Protection OfficerIKEA, Customer Support Centre, Kingston Park, Peterborough, PE2 9ET, United Kingdom
    
    01 696 6246

    You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the DPC, the Ireland regulator for data protection issues (https://www.dataprotection.ie/en). We would, however, appreciateInternalthe chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the DPC, so please contact us in the first instance.

* * *

Privacy policy for IKEA Family account
--------------------------------------

**Effective from 16/09/2026**

### 1\. About this Privacy Notice

We know how important it is for you to understand how we use your data, and we will always do our best to be transparent with you.

This Privacy Notice covers private customers who have an IKEA Family account (the “**Account**”). It explains how and why we collect, store, process and share any of the personal data you provide us when you use your IKEA Family membership in-store, online via our website and the IKEA App, on the second-hand marketplace and when you have contact with our customer support centres. All information that we have about you as a member is assigned to your IKEA Family profile.  

This Privacy Notice also tells you what your rights are in relation to the personal data that we process about you. We respect your right to privacy and are committed to maintaining it. 

*   2\. Who are we and how can you contact us?
    
    We are Ingka Group, a franchisee of Inter IKEA Systems B.V., operating digital and physical IKEA sales channels across the world. You can read more about us at www.ingka.com.
    
    The Ingka Group companies that are data controllers under this Privacy Notice are IKEA Ireland Limited (“**Local Data Controller**”) and Ingka NB AB (“**Group Data Controller**”) hereinafter referred to together as “Data Controllers” or “we”.
    
    Local Data Controller:
    
    IKEA Ireland Limited (400143)(IRE)
    
    A company registered in Ireland with its registered office at 6th Floor, 2 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2 and company number 400143.
    
    VAT number is 6420 143R.
    
    Global Data Controller:
    
    Ingka NB AB
    
    A Swedish limited liability company, registered in Sweden under number 559487-7051Registered address: Älmhultsgatan 2, 215 86 Malmö, Sweden.
    
    For the processing activities described in this Privacy Notice, we act as joint controllers as defined by Article 26 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). This means that we jointly determine the purposes and means of processing your personal data for providing the Account and its related services across Europe. Your personal data will be processed by the joint controllers for the purpose of providing you with the Account.
    
    If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice or your rights under it, please contact our local data protection officer:
    
    Email: Philip Cooke – IKEA UK&IE Data Protection Officer,

    Or contact us at: IKEA, Customer Support Centre, Kingston Park, Peterborough, PE2 9ET, United Kingdom
    
    01 696 6246
    
    If you would like to contact the Data Protection Officer of the Global Data Controller, please make the request to the local DPO using the contact details above.
    
    This Privacy Notice is only applicable to the Account and your membership in IKEA Family.
    
*   3\. Roles of the Data Controllers
    
    As joint data controllers, we will work together to offer IKEA Family and to manage your Account information. This means we both have responsibilities for looking after your data.
    
    To make it easier for you, your **Local Data Controller** is your main point of contact for any questions about your data and is responsible for handling day-to-day aspects of your Account, including most communications, the rewards and benefits associated with your Account activity and responding to your requests regarding your data.
    
    This arrangement does not affect your rights under data protection law, and you may exercise your rights in relation to your personal data against either data controller.
    
    Please note that we also act as independent data controllers for the processing of your personal data when you interact with each of us, either by – for example – making a purchase from the Local Data Controller or using the second-hand marketplace, which is operated by the Global Data Controller.
    
    *   If you are looking for the Local Data Controller’s local Privacy Notice, you can find it here [Privacy policy - IKEA Ireland](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/privacy-policy/). In this Privacy Notice, you will find information about the processing of your personal data for the purpose of things like payments, refunds, returns, delivery of IKEA products and other processing related to your purchase from IKEA Retail.
    *   If you are looking for the Global Data Controller’s Privacy Notice for IKEA Second Hand, you can find it [here](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/privacy-policy/#f43d5ad0-2837-11f1-8214-438331e3f7eb). In this Privacy Notice, you will find information about the processing of your personal data to enable your listings, interactions with other users on the second-hand marketplace and your sales or purchases on the second-hand marketplace. 
    
*   4\. Why do we collect and process your data?
    
    We offer a great variety of services, benefits and rewards to our IKEA Family members including member discounts, reward points, purchase history and access to IKEA Second Hand, which is a second-hand marketplace where you can sell and buy IKEA products to and from other IKEA Family members (the “**Marketplace**”). To be able to offer the best experience possible, we use your personal data to tailor our content, offer services, improve your personalised experience and deliver marketing messages (including advertisements and offers) to the expectations and needs of our Family Members.
    
    You will find more information about IKEA Family services, benefits and rewards in the [IKEA Family Terms and Conditions](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/terms-conditions/ikea-family-terms-and-conditions-pub6cce14b1/) (“IKEA Family T&C’s”).
    
    Additionally, collecting and processing your data allows us to provide you support where you need it, manage your requests for information and services and, where necessary, manage any complaints you may have related to your Account or IKEA Family.We will also analyse your personal data for information security and statistical purposes and share your personal data with other companies within Ingka Group where those other companies share various operations and business processes with us. We will do this in order to fulfil our contractual obligations to you, or because it is in our legitimate interests to do so. 
    
*   5\. What personal data do we process and for what purpose?
    
    When you create and use your Account we will collect and process your personal data. We may collect the following types of personal data:
    
    *   Information you provide directly to us: This may include your IKEA Family card – digital or physical – your name, home address, email address, phone number, and any other information you choose to provide when you create or use your IKEA Family Account, use your rewards, book a service, subscribe to our communications, use our Marketplace or sign up to an IKEA Family event or promotion.
    *   Information we collect automatically: When you interact with us through your Account, we will automatically collect certain information, such as your IP address, browser software, operating system, and the IKEA store from which you have accessed the Account.  
    
    Your personal data is processed for the following purposes:
    
    ### To create and manage your IKEA Family Account
    
    We process your personal data to set up and manage access to your Account. This includes confirming you meet the age requirements set out in the IKEA Family T&C’s, identifying you during purchases and interactions online, in-store and on the Marketplace and providing Account management support. Where required, we may use your social security number or other national identification details to identify you as an IKEA Family member when you don't have your digital or physical IKEA Family card in-store.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   First name
    *   Last name
    *   Title
    *   Address
    *   Email address
    *   Month and year of birth
    *   mobile telephone number
    *   IKEA Family card number
    *   Account password and login details
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We do this to perform our contract (the IKEA Family T&C’s) with you and to enable us to set up your Account and support you throughout your membership with us. Optional personal data is processed with your consent, and you can choose to not provide this information if you do not wish to. 
    
    ### To provide you with services based on your location
    
    We use information you share with us about your location to determine your nearest IKEA store to identify your preferred retail market. This serves as your primary location for using IKEA Family services.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Preferred store
    *   Location data (country and zip code)
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We have a legitimate interest in providing our websites to you in the correct language and up to date store information.
    
    ### To deliver our customer support services to you
    
    We process the data from chat interactions you have on the IKEA website and the Marketplace to provide customer support services for requests and Account management. We also use this data to follow up on complaints and improve systems and services offered through understanding system performance and activity.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Customer ID, name and contact information
    *   Chat data and chat history
    *   The type of service request
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We process this personal data in order to fulfil our contract (the IKEA Family T&C’s) with you, and to ensure that you have a smooth experience and to resolve issues you encounter when using your Account. 
    
    ### To personalise your experience as an IKEA Family member on our website, app and Marketplace
    
    We personalise your shopping experience by performing analysis on user activity data to generate customer insight. If you give us your consent to do this, we will provide you with tailored content, product recommendations, targeted offers, and personalised marketing messages.
    
    If you choose to share your data about your home and interests with us, we will use this to provide you with better product recommendations.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Browsing history
    *   Shopping preferences
    *   Wish lists
    *   Homeowner status (optional)
    *   Number of children (optional)
    *   Categories of interest (optional)
    *   Hashed email address
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We will personalise your online experience where you have consented to the use of cookies on our website or Marketplace or where you have provided consent in your Account to use your wish lists, categories of interest and home information. You can manage your cookies and update your preferences at any time.
    
    ### To provide IKEA Family members with home planning and consultation services
    
    When you book a planning or consultation service using your Account, we use your personal data to:
    
    *   Identify you as an IKEA Family Member.
    *   Save outcomes to your Account.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Account data
    *   Home details
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We need to process your personal data in order to fulfil our contract (the IKEA Family T&C’s) with you. 
    
    ### To send you direct marketing messages as an IKEA Family member
    
    You will receive direct marketing messages including offers, promotions and events when you have actively given your consent to receiving such targeted communication. This may include analysis of your transaction data and purchasing information to deliver personalised direct marketing. The Local Data Controller and the Global Data Controller have jointly decided that all such direct marketing messages will be sent by the Local Data Controller.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Email address
    *   Order history and purchasing/selling activity (on the website, in the app or on the Marketplace)
    *   Phone number (optional)
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We will do this where you have provided your consent to the Local Data Controller. This consent is collected at the time of Account creation and can be updated at any time.
    
    ### To publish your ratings and reviews
    
    If you choose to share a rating or make a review, we will use this to improve our products and/or services and share it with other IKEA customers through our websites and app. Since IKEA is a global brand, your rating and review may be shared with customers in other countries we other IKEA retailers operate. Your ratings and reviews will be published with an abbreviation of your name or a nickname, such as only the first name or initials. We will however have access to your full post for moderation purposes.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Account data
    *   Your rating and review
    *   Photos that you share as part of the review
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We have legitimate interest to use your rating and review to improve our products and services. We also rely on legitimate interest as the legal basis for publishing your rating and review on our web and app.
    
    ### To help us track performance and improve our services
    
    We use your interaction data to analyse trends and identify internal improvements to the performance and usage of IKEA Family. We conduct data analytics on IKEA Family account activity at an aggregated level or use pseudonymised data to allow us to monitor performance and continually improve.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Account dataonline interactions
    *   Browsing history
    *   Shopping preferences
    *   Wish lists
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We have legitimate interest in analysing this information to improve customer experience. Your cookie consent is used for browsing history to support this analysis. We use your Account to understand your preferences and wish lists where these have been provided within your Account profile. You can manage your cookies and update your preferences at any time.
    
    ### To meet our legal obligations
    
    We process data to detect and prevent fraud as well as for auditing and security purposes.
    
    **Data processed**
    
    *   National Identification details (incl Personal Public Service (PPS) number) 
    *   Full IP Address (Metadata)
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We need to do this to comply with our legal obligations.
    
    ### Cookies and tracking technologies
    
    We use technologies, such as cookies, to enable the core functionality of our website and apps. This can include cookies that allow you to log-in to your Account and cookies that remember items you have placed in your cart.
    
    We also use technologies similar to cookies, such as pixels, for analytical and performance purposes. If you have given consent, we may use the information collected to optimise your browsing experience or obtain aggregate data about traffic and interaction on the Marketplace.
    
    Please see our [cookie policy](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/cookie-policy/) for more information.
    
    **Data processed**
    
    *   Browsing activity
    *   Full IP Address (Metadata) 
    *   Device information (device type, operating system, browser type and version) 
    *   Interactions with our online tools and services (e.g. shopping card, order placement stage, design tools)
    *   Interactions with our marketing communications 
    *   Similar information from third-party websites and apps  
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We have a legitimate interest in ensuring the functionality of the website and the Marketplace and these functional cookies will always be kept on. Use of additional cookies for analytical and personalisation purposes is based on the consent your provide to us in the cookie banner on our websites. You can update your cookie consent at any time.
    
*   7\. How long do we keep your data?
    
    We keep your personal data as long you are an IKEA Family member. Sometimes, we may keep certain data for a shorter or longer period of time, for business and operational reasons, or based on legal obligations. The time we keep your personal data depends on the purpose it was collected for, so this can differ case by case. When we no longer need your personal data for the intended purpose(s), the data will be deleted or anonymised so you can no longer be identified. An exception applies when we are required to store personal data for a longer period of time based on applicable laws and legislations.
    
*   8\. Who has access to your personal data?
    
    ### Companies that provide services to us
    
    We use third-party service providers (“**service providers**”) to process your personal data, on our behalf, and in accordance with the instructions provided by us, in strict compliance with applicable legislation, as well as this Privacy Notice.
    
    Service providers include, but are not limited to:
    
    *   Third parties who provide digital services to us so that we can operate IKEA Family.
    *   Third parties who help us segment and understand our customers.
    *   Companies that provide advertising and marketing services to us.
    *   Companies that aggregate and/or anonymise clickstream of behaviour on our website, app and Marketplace.
    
    Our Service providers will not transmit your data to other entities without our approval and without an applicable legal basis for such transmission. We undertake to only contract with entities that offer adequate guarantees of the implementation of technical and organisational measures to ensure the protection of your rights. All service providers will be bound by a written contract that regulates, among other things, the subject matter and duration of the processing, the nature and purpose thereof, the categories of data subjects, and the rights and obligations of the parties.
    
    ### Other recipients
    
    We may share your personal data with third parties (including public authorities and governmental bodies) when necessary for the purposes of (i) fulfilling our obligations under the IKEA Family T&C’s or (ii) complying with legal obligations.
    
    We may also share the personal data we collect with other companies in Ingka Group where those other companies share various operations and business processes with us. We will do this to fulfil our contractual obligations to you, or because we have a legitimate interest to do so.
    
    We share data with Inter IKEA Group Companies (such as the IKEA franchisor Inter IKEA Systems B.V). Most of the data that we share is not personal data. If we do share personal data, this is only done in a pseudonymised form. This means that the data has been edited and/or encrypted so that Inter IKEA Group Companies cannot trace the data back to you. Inter IKEA Group Companies use the pseudonymised data that we share with them to maintain and develop the IKEA concept, IKEA products and IKEA services. You find more information and contact details of Inter IKEA Systems B.V. on [This is Inter IKEA Group - Inter IKEA Group](https://www.inter.ikea.com/en/this-is-inter-ikea-group). The processing of these data is based on the legal ground of legitimate interest.
    
*   9\. International Data Transfers
    
    We may transfer personal data overseas to companies within Ingka Group (where those companies share various operations and business processes with us) or to our service providers. This may require processing of personal data in a country outside of the EEA. In those cases, the transfer of your personal data has been made lawful through an adequacy decision by the European Commission or because we have secured the transfer by entering into the standard contractual clauses (as approved by the European Commission) with the recipient. We will take steps to ensure that the transfer of your personal data outside of the European Union receives an adequate level of protection as it does in the European Union and if necessary, use other valid transfer tools or derogation in line with applicable data protection laws in order to protect and secure your personal data.
    
    If you would like further information about international data transfers and the safeguards that we have implemented to ensure the protection of your personal data, please contact us as set out in section 10 below. 
    
*   10\. Your rights
    
    Under privacy laws, including the General Data Protection Regulation (“**GDPR**”), you have a number of rights in relation the personal data that we hold about you. You may exercise these rights at any time by contacting us using the details set out below:
    
    Email: Philip Cooke – IKEA UK&IE Data Protection Officer,

    Or contact us at: IKEA, Customer Support Centre, Kingston Park, Peterborough, PE2 9ET, United Kingdom
    
    01 696 6246
    
    The access, rights and controls might vary depending on your request, however, in general the following rights are available to you, unless we communicate or justify otherwise.
    
    **Access:** You are entitled to gain confirmation from us about the personal data that we process about you, and, where that is the case, access to the personal data.
    
    **Rectification:** You are entitled to ask us to update and amend your personal data that might be inaccurate, incomplete or outdated.
    
    **Erasure (“right to be forgotten”)**: You are entitled to request us to delete personal data which is no longer necessary for its purpose.
    
    **Restriction:** You are entitled to ask us to temporarily or permanently restrict/stop some of the processing of your personal data.
    
    **Objection:** You are entitled to at any time, object to the processing of your personal data when the legal ground for processing this personal data is our legitimate interest. In certain cases, accommodating to your request could make it impossible for us to provide you with access to the Account and the IKEA Family benefits and services.
    
    **Right to withdraw your consent:** Where we base our processing of your personal data on your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You can exercise this right by changing the settings in your Account or by contacting us as set out in section 2 above. Please note that withdrawing your consent does not affect the lawfulness of the processing carried out before the withdrawal.
    
    **Data portability**: You are entitled to receive a readable copy of your personal data and, if requested, have the personal data to be transferred to another service provider.
    
    **Not be subject to automated decision-making:** You are entitled to not be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which creates legal effects concerning you, or similarly significantly affects you.
    
    **Right to complain:** You have the right to complain to us if you believe we have not complied with data protection law when using your personal data. We will acknowledge your complaint within 30 days and respond without undue delay.
    
    You also have the right to complain to the Irish Data Protection Commission (“**DPC**”). Making a complaint will not affect any other legal rights or remedies available to you.
    
    We may need to request specific information from you to confirm your identity (or to confirm that someone is authorised to act on your behalf). This is to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to anyone who has no right to receive it. Where we request information to confirm identity or to clarify your request, the time limit for responding runs from when we receive that information.
    
    We respond to rights requests without undue delay and usually within one calendar month. If your request is complex or you have made a number of requests, we may extend the time to respond by up to a further two months. If we extend the deadline, we will tell you within one month and explain why.
    
*   11\. How will I know if this Privacy Notice has changed?
    
    As privacy regulations change and we develop our processes and services, we may make changes to this Privacy Notice. All future changes to our Privacy Notice will be updated online and accessed online with the last date of update displayed as below. If we make material changes to the Privacy Notice we will also inform you by email.
    
    We encourage you to review this Privacy Notice regularly for any changes. Your continued use of your Account and our services after any implemented changes or revision to this Privacy Notice shall indicate that you have been duly informed of the revised terms for processing your personal data.

This Privacy Notice was last updated on **September 2026**.

Marketplace Privacy policy for IKEA second-hand
-----------------------------------------------

**Effective from 16/09/2026**

### 1\. About this Privacy Notice 

We know how important it is for you to understand how we use your data, and we will always do our best to be transparent with you. This Privacy Notice covers how and why we collect, store, process and share any of the personal data you provide us when you use the second-hand marketplace made available to you at [https://secondhand.ikea.com](https://secondhand.ikea.com/) (the “**Marketplace**”) for the sale and purchase of second-hand IKEA furniture and home furnishing accessories.  

This Privacy Notice also tells you what your rights are in relation to the personal data that we process about you. We respect your right to privacy and are committed to maintaining it.

The second-hand marketplace is only available to IKEA Family members. You can read about the processing of personal data for the purposes of offering you IKEA Family and the connected IKEA Family account [here](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/privacy-policy/#25424b50-2837-11f1-8214-438331e3f7eb). The terms and conditions applicable to your IKEA Family membership (including your access to the Marketplace) can be found [here](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/terms-conditions/ikea-family-terms-and-conditions-pub6cce14b1/) (“**IKEA Family T&C’s**”). This Privacy Notice is only about the processing of your personal data when you use the Marketplace and interact with other users of the Marketplace. 

*   2\. Who are we and how can you contact us?
    
    We are Ingka Group, a franchisee of Inter IKEA Systems B.V., operating digital and physical IKEA sales channels across the world. You can read more about us at www.ingka.com.
    
    The Ingka Group company that is data controller under this Privacy Notice is Ingka NB AB hereinafter referred to as “**Data Controller**” or “**we**”. Ingka NB AB is a Swedish limited liability company, registered with the Swedish Companies house under registration number 559487-7051, having its registered address at Älmhultsgatan 2, 215 86 Malmö, Sweden. Ingka NB AB is the operator of the Marketplace.
    
    If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice or your rights set out in section 8 above, please contact our Data Protection Officer [here](mailto:groupdpo.dataprotectionoficer.se@ingka.ikea.com) or send a letter to our registered address set out above, with attention “Data Protection Officer”. 
    
*   3\. What personal data do we process and for what purpose?
    
    When you use the Marketplace, we will collect and process your personal data. We may collect the following types of personal data:
    
    *   **Information you provide directly to us:** This includes your IKEA Family profile (for log-in purposes), your published listings including photos, chat messages that you type and reviews that you make, and any other information you choose to provide when you use the Marketplace.
    *   **Information we collect automatically:** When you interact with us on the Marketplace, we will automatically collect certain information, such as your IP address, browser software and operating system.
    *   **Information we receive from others:** We receive personal data about you from our payment service provider and we may also receive personal data from other Marketplace users if they rate and review you.
    
    Your personal data is processed for the following purposes:
    
    ### To identify you as an IKEA Family member and make the Marketplace work for you
    
    In order to access the Marketplace, you will need to log in with your IKEA Family account. We need to know where you are located to present the right country and language version of the Marketplace to you. We will also process your personal data to enable you to list second-hand IKEA products that you want to sell, and to browse and purchase second-hand IKEA products from others.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Email address and password
    *   Your IKEA Family ID number
    *   Country of residence/zip code
    *   Listings (including photos and descriptions)
    *   Purchase and sale history and transaction ID
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We do this to perform our contract (the IKEA Family T&C’s) with you to enable us to grant you access to the Marketplace.
    
    ### To facilitate the communication between buyers and sellers
    
    We will process your personal data to make available the chat functionality to help the interaction between buyers and sellers. We apply automatic content moderation of the chat messages to ensure they comply with the IKEA Family T&C’s. For the same reason, we will review your message if another user has flagged it as inappropriate. We may also process the chat messages if needed to manage an issue raised under the Buyer Protection.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   User name
    *   Chat messages
    *   Product questions
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We process this personal data to perform our contract (the IKEA Family T&C’s) and because we have a legal obligation to take action if content is flagged as illegal or inappropriate.
    
    ### To enable ratings and reviews
    
    The Marketplace allows for users to rate and review other users. All ratings and reviews are subject to moderation. When published, they will indicate the username of both the one publishing the review, and the one subject to the review.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Username of the one making a review
    *   Username of the one subject to a review
    *   Product(s) sold
    *   Rating and review data
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We process this personal data to perform our contract (the IKEA Family T&C’s).
    
    ### To facilitate payment
    
    We will process your personal data to facilitate the payment process, whether you make a payment or receive payment through a bank transfer or an IKEA digital refund card. The payment is handled by an external payment service provider. We will share your bank account details, billing/shipping address, name and last name, date, time and amount of purchase, device ID, order ID, payment card details and customer identifiers to the transaction, with the payment service provider. If requested by the payment service provider for the purpose of e.g. KYC controls (know-your-customer) or fraud prevention, we may also ask you to share your tax ID and official/national identification number.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   First name and last name
    *   Date, time and amount of purchase
    *   Bank account details
    *   Billing/shipping address
    *   Device ID
    *   Order ID
    *   Payment card details
    *   Customer identifiers
    *   Tax ID or official/national identification number
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We process this personal data to perform our contract (the IKEA Family T&C’s). For the purpose of KYC and fraud prevention we process the personal data based on our legal obligation to do so.
    
    ### To deliver our customer support services to you
    
    We process the data from support chat interactions you have with us on the Marketplace to provide customer support services. We also use this data to follow up on complaints and improve systems and services offered through understanding system performance and activity.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Customer ID, name and contact information
    *   The type of service request
    *   Attachments (if any) of information supporting the request
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We process this personal data in order to fulfil our contract (the IKEA Family T&C’s) with you, and to ensure that you have a smooth experience and to resolve issues you encounter when using the Marketplace.
    
    ### To personalise your experience on the Marketplace
    
    We personalise your experience on the Marketplace by performing analysis on user activity data to generate customer insight. These customer insights help us tailor your feed, recommend listings that are relevant for you and present relevant search results.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Browsing history
    *   Activity data (e.g. purchases, published listings, sold item and searches)
    *   Alerts
    *   Location data (to show listings near you)
    *   Hashed email address
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We will personalise your online experience based on your cookie consent and where applicable our legitimate interest to create an inspiring Marketplace that is relevant to you.
    
    ### To report transactions to the tax authorities
    
    We will process your personal data to report your identity to the Swedish tax authorities (and your local tax authority) if your total sales and/or number of transactions reach the threshold set out in applicable tax legislation (implementing the DAC7 directive).
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   First name and last name
    *   Address
    *   Tax ID or official/national identification number
    *   Date of birth
    *   Total value of sales on the Marketplace during the current year
    *   Number of transactions
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We process this personal data to perform our legal obligation under applicable tax legislation (DAC7).
    
    ### To help us track performance and improve our services
    
    We use your interaction data to analyse trends and identify internal improvements to the performance and usage of the Marketplace. We conduct data analytics on Marketplace activity at an aggregated level or use pseudonymised data to allow us to monitor performance and continually improve.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   Account data
    *   Online interactions
    *   Browsing history
    *   Shopping preferences
    *   Alerts
    *   Navigation and connectivity information
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We have legitimate interest in analysing this information to improve customer experience. Your cookie consent is used for browsing history to support this analysis. We use your user profile to understand your preferences and alerts where these have been provided within your user profile. You can manage your cookies and update your preferences at any time. This data will be linked to a pseudonymized identifier as a measure to protect your identity.
    
    ### To help us secure that the Marketplace is safe to use
    
    We use your personal data to make sure that our Marketplace is a safe space for everyone. This means that we process personal data to prevent and protect us and you from fraud and scams, to make your payments secure and to make sure that all users comply with the IKEA Family T&C’s that apply to the Marketplace. This also means that we moderate the Marketplace for suspicious activity and take action when users flag illegal content.
    
    **Personal Data processed**
    
    *   User ID
    *   Account data
    *   Activity data
    *   Device and technical data, IP address
    *   Location data
    *   Chat messages
    
    **Legal basis**
    
    We have legitimate interest to prevent and protect you and us from misuse and abuse of the Marketplace, fraud and security threats. In addition to this, we have a legal obligation as a platform operator to take action when we become aware of illegal activities on our Marketplace and to save such information for the period set out in the European Digital Services Act. 
    
*   4\. How long do we keep your data?
    
    We keep your personal data as long as needed for the purposes set out above. When we no longer need your personal data for the intended purpose(s), the data will be deleted or anonymised so you can no longer be identified. Sometimes, we may keep certain data for a shorter or longer period of time, for business and operational reasons, or based on legal obligations.
    
*   5\. Who has access to your personal data?
    
    We use third-party service providers (“**service providers**”) to process your personal data, on our behalf, and in accordance with the instructions provided by us, in strict compliance with applicable legislation, as well as this Privacy Notice.
    
    Service providers include, but are not limited to:
    
    *   Third parties who provide digital services to us so that we can operate the Marketplace.
    *   Third parties who help us segment and understand our customers.
    *   Companies that provide advertising and marketing services to us.
    *   Companies that aggregate and/or anonymise clickstream of behaviour on our website, app and Marketplace.
    
    Our service providers will not transmit your data to other entities without our approval and without an applicable legal basis for such transmission. We undertake to only contract with entities that offer adequate guarantees of the implementation of technical and organisational measures to ensure the protection of your rights. All service providers will be bound by a written contract that regulates, among other things, the subject matter and duration of the processing, the nature and purpose thereof, the categories of data subjects, and the rights and obligations of the parties.
    
    Furthermore, we may transmit or communicate your personal data to third parties (including public authorities and governmental bodies) when necessary for the purposes of (i) fulfilling our obligations under the IKEA Family T&C’s, and (ii) complying with legal obligations.
    
    Lastly, other Marketplace users will have access to some of your personal data (username, listings, location, ratings and reviews) which is needed for them to interact with you on the Marketplace. When you have sold a product, the buyer will also have access to the pick-up address you have specified in your profile.
    
*   6\. Automated Decision Making
    
    We leverage artificial intelligence (AI) tools to proactively identify and flag content, listings, or user behaviour on the Marketplace that potentially violates applicable law and/or our moderation policies. However, to ensure fairness and accuracy, all content flagged by AI will undergo a mandatory review by a human moderator. This process guarantees that no decisions regarding content removal, user warnings, or account actions are made solely by automated means, thereby upholding our commitment to human oversight and compliance with regulations on automated decision-making.
    
*   7\. International Data Transfers
    
    We may transfer personal data overseas to companies within Ingka Group (where those companies share various operations and business processes with us) or to our service providers. This may require processing of personal data in a country outside of the EEA. In those cases, the transfer of your personal data has been made lawful through an adequacy decision by the European Commission or because we have secured the transfer by entering into the standard contractual clauses (as approved by the European Commission) with the recipient. We will take steps to ensure that the transfer of your personal data outside of the EEA receives an adequate level of protection as it does in the EEA and if necessary, use other valid transfer tools or derogation in line with applicable data protection laws in order to protect and secure your personal data.
    
    If you would like further information about international data transfers and the safeguards that we have implemented to ensure the protection of your personal data, please contact us as set out in section 2 above. 
    
*   8\. Your rights
    
    Under privacy laws, including the General Data Protection Regulation (“**GDPR**”), the UK General Data Protection Regulation and the Swiss Data Protection Act in force since 1 September 2023, you have a number of rights in relation the personal data that we hold about you. You may exercise these rights at any time by sending a request through:
    
    Email: Philip Cooke – IKEA UK&IE Data Protection Officer, dataprotection.officer.ie@ingka.ikea.com
    
    Or contact us at: IKEA, Customer Support Centre, Kingston Park, Peterborough, PE2 9ET, United Kingdom
    
    01 696 6246
    
    The access, rights and controls might vary depending on your request, however, in general the following rights are available to you, unless we communicate or justify otherwise.
    
    **Access:** You are entitled to gain confirmation from us about the personal data that we process about you, and, where that is the case, access to the personal data.
    
    **Rectification:** You are entitled to ask us to update and amend your personal data that might be inaccurate, incomplete or outdated.
    
    **Erasure (“right to be forgotten”)**: You are entitled to request us to delete personal data which is no longer necessary for its purpose.
    
    **Restriction:** You are entitled to ask us to temporarily or permanently restrict/stop some of the processing of your personal data.
    
    **Objection:** You are entitled to at any time, object to the processing of your personal data when the legal ground for processing this personal data is our legitimate interest. In certain cases, accommodating to your request could make it impossible for us to provide you with access to the Marketplace.
    
    **Right to withdraw your consent:** If we base our processing of your personal data on your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You can exercise this right by contacting us as set out in section 2 above. Please note that withdrawing your consent does not affect the lawfulness of the processing carried out before the withdrawal.
    
    **Data portability:** You are entitled to receive a readable copy of your personal data and, if requested, have the personal data to be transferred to another service provider.
    
    Not be subject to automated decision-making: You are entitled to not be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which creates legal effects concerning you, or similarly significantly affects you.
    
    Right to complain: You have the right to send a complaint about our use of your personal data to your local data protection authority. However, before doing so, we would of course love to hear from you and get the chance to address your concern.
    
    Making a complaint to your local data protection authority will not affect any other legal rights or remedies that might be available to you under law.
    
    We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is to ensure your personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
    
    We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one calendar month. Occasionally it could take us longer than this if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 
    
*   9\. How will I know if this Privacy Notice has changed?
    
    As privacy regulations change and we develop our processes and services, we may make changes to this Privacy Notice. All future changes to our Privacy Notice will be updated online and accessed online with the last date of update displayed as below. If we make material changes to the Privacy Notice we will also inform you by email.
    
    We encourage you to review this Privacy Notice regularly for any changes. Your continued use of the Marketplace after any implemented changes or revision to this Privacy Notice shall indicate that you have been duly informed of the revised terms for processing your personal data.

This Privacy Notice was last updated on **September 2026**.

* * *

Privacy policy for IKEA for Business account and IKEA Business Network
----------------------------------------------------------------------

We know how important it is for you to understand how we use your data. This Privacy Policy sets out how and why we collect, use, store and share your personal data when you sign up as a registered user of your company’s IKEA for Business Account (the “Account”). 

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully and if you have any questions or concerns about how we use your personal data, please contact IKEA Customer Support Centre and we will try to address your concerns. Our Customer Support Centre can also put you in contact with our Data Protection Officer if you have more specific questions or concerns.  

We are IKEA Ireland Limited (“I**KEA**” or “**we**”, “**us**”), and our registered address is 6th Floor, 2 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2. We are part of Ingka Group, which means we are ultimately owned by Ingka Holding B.V. IKEA Iis the data controller of any personal data it collects, processes and holds about you in relation to your use of the Account. 

*   What personal data is collected and why?
    
     It is completely voluntary to sign up as a user of the Account. However, if you do, we need to know who you are so that we can administrate and secure the Account, enable the functionalities connected to the Account and communicate with you in various matters related thereto. For these purposes we will collect your name, email address and telephone number (optional) and number of the IKEA for Business Card that we issue for you. We will also collect and store information about the purchases that you have made on behalf of your company as well as your other activities on the Account. The information about the purchase history and user activity may be used to send tailored direct marketing if you have specifically consented to receiving such communication. 
    
*   Legal ground for processing 
    
    The legal ground for the processing of your personal data is our legitimate interest to administer your use of the Account, provide the features and functionality that we have offered to your company and to collect statistics on how our customers use their IKEA for Business Accounts. We will send you marketing emails only if you have specifically consented to receiving such messages and you can always opt out by clicking on the link in the bottom of each email you receive from us. 
    
*   Who has access to your data? 
    
    The administrator of the Account (which is a person within your company) will be able to see the purchases that you have made on behalf of the company and registered on the Account. The Account is operated by IKEA IT AB (which is another company in Ingka Group) and its trusted internal as well as third party service providers. Such service providers may be located outside of the European Union, in which case the transfer of your personal data is secured by additional safeguards, such as e.g. an agreement incorporating standard data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission. 
    
    Your rights You have a number of rights relating to your personal data and what happens to it. You are entitled to: 
    
    *   have your data processed in a fair, lawful and transparent way; 
    *   be informed about how your personal data is being used, an example being this privacy policy; 
    *   access personal data we hold about you;
    *   require us to correct any mistakes in your personal data; 
    *   require us to delete personal data concerning you in certain situations where there is no good reason for us to continue to process it; 
    *   request that we transfer your personal data to you or another service provider in a simple, structured format; 
    *   object at any time to processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes; 
    *   object to automated decision making which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you; 
    *   object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal data and 
    *   otherwise restrict or temporarily stop our processing of your personal data in certain circumstances. 
    
    You can read more about your rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, in the Guidance from the Irish Data Protection Commissioner (DPC) [https://www.dataprotection.ie/](https://www.dataprotection.ie/). You also have the right to complain about our use of personal data to the DPC. You can do these by contacting the DPC via their website [https://www.dataprotection.ie/en/individuals/raising-concern-commission](https://www.dataprotection.ie/en/individuals/raising-concern-commission) or by emailing [info@dataprotection.ie](mailto:info@dataprotection.ie). If you would like to speak to us in relation to any of your rights, please [contact us](https://www.ikea.com/ie/en/customer-service/contact-us/). 
    
*   How long will we keep your data? 
    
    We will keep your personal data as long as you are a registered user of the Account. All personal data will be deleted when the Account is terminated.  
    
*   How will we secure your data? 
    
    We take the security of your personal data very seriously. We have implemented various strategies, controls, policies and measures to keep your data secure and keep these measures under close review. We protect your data by using encryption techniques and we use other safeguards such as firewalls and password protection. We do our best to ensure that your data is protected and only accessible to Ingka Group employees (or subcontractors) who need it to carry out their job responsibilities. 
    
*   Contact 
    
    If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or your rights under it, please contact Philip Cooke – IKEA UK&IE Data Protection Officer IKEA Ireland Limited, Customer Support Centre, Kingston Park, Peterborough, PE2 9ET, United Kingdom 
    
    01 696 6246

    Version I, date of publishing December 2021 

Date Updated: **January 2025**
